moving averages are not some magic
secret that will instantly make you
profitable but neither is anything else
you will ever learn about trading you
see profitable trading actually comes
down to utilizing multiple technical
factors like indicators and price action
in order to create a perfect trading
scenario that gives you a statistic
advantage over the market that plays out
over time and that is exactly how any
professional Trader has positive returns
so in this video you'll be learning
about moving averages themselves as well
as a complete moving average trading
strategy that will help you point out
accurate trades this strategy is simple
enough for beginners but so powerful
that I still use it in my own trading to
this day so if that sounds interesting
to you go ahead and click that like
button for me go ahead and subscribe if
you are new and I'll see you right after
the intro and
[Music]
disclaimer welcome back and let's go
ahead and get started the first thing
I'm going to do for any of you who are
brand new to trading is explain what
moving averages are and how we can
utilize them to help us make more
accurate trading decisions let's go
ahead and Jump Right In moving averages
are probably the most simple indicator
that you can plot on a chart so to get
you an example of this the three most
popular moving averages are the 20
period moving average the 50 period
moving average and the 200 period moving
average so to put this really simply and
to make sure you have a complete
understanding of what these do we're
going to look at the 200 period moving
average because it is the most popular
so this box you see on the screen
represents 200 candles from the most
recent candle printed by Price all the
way back to the beginning of the Box
this moving average is a line plotted on
the chart based on the close of the most
recent 200 candles So based on the
latest 200 candles the average price of
all of those candles together is
0.897 to here on the 4-Hour chart of the
Aussie Canada and the 200 before the
moving average just refers to the look
back period so that just refers to the
amount of candles we're looking back at
if we were on a daily chart we'd be
looking at 200 days of data if we were
on a minute chart we'd see the average
of the last 200 minutes of price when
looking at our moving average price now
we're taking a look at the 50 period
moving average and to make sure this is
perfectly clear for beginners that blue
line you see is the 50 period moving
average we're going to dive into the
settings for this right now so on the
settings you'll see inputs length refers
to the look back period how many candles
do we want this moving average to
calculate based on the source I never
change it's always on close and I never
mess with the offset but if I wanted to
look at a 20 period moving average I
would just change the length from 50 to
20 and that would change the moving
average on the chart but with this being
the 50 period moving average all that
means is that the price of the 50 EMA at
the moment being
0.905 55 is the average of the last 50
candles we can see in our box closing
prices and the exact same thing applies
to any length or period you place in
this box so hopefully that gives you a
clear understanding of what moving
averages are now how do we utilize these
in order to make more accurate trading
decisions well moving averages for me
only serve two purposes the first
purpose is to help me identify the trend
of a particular market and I don't just
utilize a moving average for this but
when combining the moving average with
price action as you'll learn how to do a
little later in the video it can really
help to add accuracy to your Trend
identification the next thing I utilize
moving averages for is for areas of
value that can create zones that I can
potentially buy from or sell from
depending if I want to go long or short
on a particular asset the 50 period
moving average is by far the moving
average I use most in my trading Now by
itself the 50 period moving average does
not mean much but when you combine it
with a very specific set of technical
factors something amazing happens it
helps to produce a profitable trading
strategy that can give an edge over the
market so with that being the case now
I'm going to be showing you a full
trading strategy that utilizes the 50
period moving average in combination
with other technical factors that I
utilize in my trading right now and that
helps me pull profits out of the market
a trading strategy is simply a set of
rules or combination of technical
factors that give you a perfect trading
scenario that you can replicate in order
to pull profits out of the market over
time so a good trading strategy should
really act like a checklist where you're
just checking off each rule you have
until your entry criteria is met and
then you place a trade when your entry
criteria is met and yes trading can be
that simple but the strategy is normally
not the Super difficult part normally
the difficult part is having good enough
Trading cyle pschology to not switch
strategies constantly or break your
rules and having good risk management
but this video specifically is about the
strategy so let's dive into it right now
as I said your strategy should just act
as a checklist so here you can see six
rules that we must see met in order to
place a trade based on the trading
strategy you're learning right now let's
go ahead and dive in by taking a look at
rule number one the first rule is going
to help us identify the trend of the
market this is a trend continuation
Strate
so in order to identify the trend the
way we're going to do that is by looking
at Price along with the 50 period moving
average which is the blue line on the
chart and ensuring that we have a new
high in price compared to the most
recent high and ensuring that all this
has happened above the 50 period moving
average if that is the case we have rule
number one met for a bullish entry but
we have more rules more conditions we
need to see rule number two we then want
to see a pullback that gets close to or
touches the 50 period moving average so
after identifying Trend our next step is
to identify an area of value that's
likely to push the market higher into
Trend continuation and one of the ways I
utilize the 50 period moving average is
by using it as a area of value and as
you can see we're just checking off
rules on our checklist and again this is
how any good strategy should be set up
here we do in fact get a pullback that
comes down and touches the blue line or
our 5050 EMA now our third rule for this
strategy is that this pullback not only
needs to touch the 50 EMA but also must
align with a structure level that's been
tested at least twice by previous price
the way I normally do this is by
creating an area near where price
currently is because areas of value are
always zones not just specific lines on
the chart after I have this area created
all I have to do is look back in the
past and say has this area been tested
multiple times the answer here is yes we
have one two three recent tests of this
exact area so at this point we've
combined price and the 50 period moving
average to identify that we are in an
uptrend we've also utilized the 50
period moving average and levels of
structure to identify that we're in an
area value that could push price higher
and continue this most recent uptrend
price has started these are all the
conditions of the strategy meaning the
next thing we're going to look for is an
entry criteria and the way I do that is
by looking for buying pressure in this
Zone and as you can see here buying
pressure is just a close above candle so
let's check out what that looks like
right now a close above candle is a very
simple Candlestick pattern formation
after all of our other criterias met we
are in an uptrend we're in our area
value Zone we' pointed out now we're
looking for this Candlestick pattern
formation you see on the chart now all a
close above candle is is a candle that
closes above the high of the previous
candle now why is this something we
would want to look for because this type
of Candlestick can show us buying
pressure so if we already have all of
our other criteria in place we already
know the trend we're in is up we already
know that we're in an area of value
based on multiple indications utilizing
structure and the 50 period moving
average at this point if we see buying
pressure in this Zone then from my
testing and experience in the market we
have an advantage here that plays out
over time that does not mean every
single time I place a trade like this it
wins that means that out of a hundred
times I place a trade like this and I
place it with that exact same checklist
every single time I utilize good risk
management and decent position
management that over that 100 Trade
sample size I will be profitable so in
this case with this being our actual
entry criteria this is when I would
place the trade now outside of the entry
criteria we also need rules for stops
and targets otherwise we're going to be
in a mess so let's go ahead and talk
about rules for stops and Targets in
terms of the stop loss I always just put
it in a logical position so most of the
time that's going to be below the swing
low before that close above candle and
the reason for that is if this close
above candle does not create buying
pressure and instead we see sellers
start to Take Back Control then I'm
likely wrong about what I think is going
to happen here with price and with that
being the case I want to get out as soon
as possible at the least amount of risk
as possible so that's why my stop loss
is going to go below that swing low in
terms of targets for the sake of this
video we're just going to be utilizing a
2:1 reward to risk ratio which happens
to line up really nicely with this
previous level of structure right here
so with that being the case this trade
meets all the criteria for a bullish
entry utilizing this strategy so let's
go ahead and click play and see what
price ended up doing we did eventually
put push up high enough to hit those
targets so just to show you that I'm not
just picking out random trades and that
I actually utilize the same exact
strategy in my own trading in my real
account you can see me actually taking
profits on this exact trade I'll put
that on the screen right now also this
is a trade that I sent out to all the
members of the TTC Forex University as
an email alert so if you're someone
who's interested in taking your trading
to the next level if you want a full
trading course teaching you everything
from the basics of Forex Trading to very
Advanced strategies and if you'd like to
receive two to five email alerts like
this one each week obviously disclaimer
here they don't all win this just
happened to be one that did but if
you're interested in that then you can
get all the details for the TTC forx
University by clicking the top Link in
the description or going to
www.th trading channel.com the
University is also a mentorship program
meaning you get access to me and I will
be answering any trading related
questions that you have to ensure that
your journey is as smooth as possible to
accomplishing your trading goals so
again if you're interested in that top
Link in the description or you can go to
our website you can see on the screen if
you're not interested in that no big
deal at all let's go ahead and jump over
and take a look at a bearish version of
this strategy I almost forgot to do this
but here is the bullish and bearish
entry rules the actual checklist itself
if you feel like screenshotting this go
ahead and pause the video and do that
now all right so let's take a look at a
bearish version of this strategy what's
our first rule for a bearish version
these rules are exactly the same they're
just flipped upside down so instead of a
new high above the 50 EMA for this
version of the strategy a bearish
version where we're looking for sell
trades we actually want to see a new low
created by Price compared to the most
recent low and we want this to happen
while price is below the blue line or
the 50 EMA is that criteria met here yes
it is second criteria we want to see a
pullback that reaches our 50 EMA let's
push price forward and see if we get
that rule met so we can check it off of
our checklist yes right here we do in
fact get a pullback that comes up and
touches the 50 EMA so now we have our
Trend identified we have price at one
area value being that 50 EMA so we can
check off our first two rules but our
third rule almost said second there is
that we need to be at a level of
structure that's been tested at least
twice so how are we going to Define that
or how are we going to I guess find that
is actually by creating a box around
where current price is looking left and
asking ourselves is this an area of
structure that's been tested multiple
times by price and the answer to that is
yes we have multiple recent tests of
this area where price was pushed around
by this area so that adds to our area of
value and gives us the opportunity to
check off rule number three rule number
four is actually our entry criteria for
a bearish trade we're not going to be
looking for a close above candle but
rather a close below candle before we
can check that off and actually look to
enter the trade so let's push price
forward this is very obvious we'll get a
little closer just in case it's hard to
see but as you can see here we do in
fact have a large close below candle so
this would be my entry criteria
everything I need to be met is met for
me to actually place a trade here so on
the close of that candle is where I
would place the trade I'd be looking at
a stop loss just above the previous
swing High because in this case if this
candle does not cause selling pressure
and I'm not not going to say quickly I
don't care if price consolidates but if
it doesn't cause selling pressure before
we see price come up and break above
this swing high that was made then I'm
probably wrong and I want to be out of
the market so for that reason that's
where my stop loss is going to go and
for our targets we had a 2:1 reward to
risk ratio so this is what that exact
trade setup would look like let's go
ahead and click play and as you can see
price does eventually pushed down enough
to hit those targets I cannot stress
this enough though I'm just showing
examples here that did work out no
strategy is 100% accurate this will have
losses do your own back testing to see
what pairs it works best on and to get
an average win rate based on the way you
see the market but in this case another
successful trade utilizing this strategy
now as a special added bonus on this
video I'm actually going to take you
through the preparation I do for this by
looking at the five currency pairs I
have on my watch list for this exact
strategy going into next week so each of
the pairs we're going to take a look at
is somewhere on that list that checklist
we have and close to meeting the
criteria for this strategy and this is
just the preparation I do in order to
spot this strategy and be ready for it
to happen throughout the week so let's
take a look we're going to start off on
the Aussie dollar so on the Aussie
dollar as you can see price has just
done what we have just broke above the
50 period moving average which is our
Blue Line price has also since then
created a brand new high
above the 50 period moving average since
that is the case I am now waiting for a
pullback that happens to
coincide with this area of structure
that's been tested multiple times at the
point that this pullback happens that's
where I'll be waiting for that entry
criteria which would be a close above
candle to insinuate that we have buying
pressure in an area of value while we've
just established an uptrend and that's
when I'll be waiting to enter this
Market Market in anticipation for train
to continue to that upwards Direction
next up we're going to take a look at
the Euro Canada very similar situation
here on this pair we have price that has
just pushed above the 50 EMA after which
we created a pullback and a new high all
above the 50 period moving average after
doing this we are now waiting for a
pullback to coincide with that 50 period
moving average as well as the previous
level of structure that obviously been
tested multiple times and at that point
I'll be looking for the entry criteria
of a close above candle here on the
daily chart next we have the pound
Canada and on this pair we've just had
what we've had this move higher followed
by a pullback followed by a push into a
new high all of which is happening above
the 50 period moving average so with
this being the case I can already tell
we have an area of structure that's been
tested multiple times and if we see a
pullback on this pair or a push higher
and a pullback back will likely need to
happen and that pullback happens to
coincide with the 50 period moving
average along with this major level of
structure then at that point I'll look
for that entry criteria of a close above
candle here on the pound Canada next up
we have the Euro newand here on this
pair we're looking for a possible
shorting trade or a sell opportunity in
the bearish direction and the reason is
what is price just done we have just
pushed lower created a pullback and a
new low all happening below the blue
line or 50 period moving average so with
this being the case we are now waiting
for a pullback and that pullback to
coincide with the 50 period moving
average as well as coincide with this
previous level of structure we've
pointed out that's been tested multiple
times at that point I'll be looking for
a possible close below candle for a
short trade and next up we're looking at
the pound Aussie this pair has just
created what a new low compared to the
previous low that happened below the 50
period moving average so now just like
all the other pairs we're waiting for a
pullback that coincides with this Zone
as well as the 50 period moving average
and that pullback after it and when
price gets into our area of value we're
going to be looking for possible sell
trades in this area or at least I am
based on a close below candle for entry
I just noticed that throughout the video
I've been swapping back and forth
between saying the 50 period moving
average average and the 50 EMA which is
exponential moving average I personally
use EMAs but the difference is going to
be minuscule it's not going to matter if
you use a regular moving average or the
exponential moving average the premise
is exactly the same and it's not going
to affect the performance of the
strategy almost at all but outside of
that I hope you found today's video
valuable don't forget that we have some
space available in the TTC University so
for any of you interested in learning
more about our mentorship program go and
click that top Link in the description
or go to the trading channel.com if
you're not interested in that no big
deal at all just go ahead and click that
subscribe button if you're new to stay
up to date with all the new content we
release go ahead and click that like
button if you made it to the end also
comment below if you made it to the end
and I'll try to like every single
comment that says they made it to the
end I hope you have a great trading week
and I'll talk to you in the next video
see you soon